<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Michael Skyba</title><link>https://michaelskyba.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Michael Skyba</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 11:13:58 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://michaelskyba.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Operating Systems</title><link>https://michaelskyba.github.io/articles/operating-systems/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 11:13:58 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://michaelskyba.github.io/articles/operating-systems/</guid><description>In this &amp;ldquo;article&amp;rdquo;, I will write about several different operating systems that I have used. I am not an expert on any of them and there is a high chance that none of my rambling will be useful to anybody. I am mostly writing this &amp;ldquo;for fun&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;for myself&amp;rdquo;, if that makes sense.
Desktop Windows 10 When I first got my laptop, which is the computer I&amp;rsquo;ve used for most of my life, it came with Windows 10, which I used for a while.</description></item><item><title>Scripture</title><link>https://michaelskyba.github.io/articles/scripture/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 10:59:07 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://michaelskyba.github.io/articles/scripture/</guid><description>This article is about scripture, an SM-2 implementation that I made. This will not be a rewrite of the README but instead notes on why I made it, my workflow with it, etc.
SM-2 SM-2 is an application of spaced repetition. The idea is to be able to retain information in your long-term memory while spending as little total time as possible reviewing it. SM-2 is a popular algorithm due to it proving to be effective.</description></item><item><title>Deltarune Chapter 1 on Linux</title><link>https://michaelskyba.github.io/articles/deltarune-chapter-1-on-linux/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 10:53:42 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://michaelskyba.github.io/articles/deltarune-chapter-1-on-linux/</guid><description>With the release of Deltarune Chapter 2 today, I thought I would share how I was able to get Chapter 1 working on Linux. I will assume you&amp;rsquo;re running Arch.
1. Download the .exe This would be from Deltarune&amp;rsquo;s website.
2. Install Wine and libstrangle su -c &amp;#34;pacman -S wine&amp;#34; git clone https://aur.archlinux.org/libstrangle-git.git cd libstrangle-git makepkg -sirc 3. Install Deltarune as if you were on Windows using Wine wine SURVEY_PROGRAM_WINDOWS_ENGLISH.exe For me, it stopped writing new text after a couple of minutes, at which point I killed it with ^C.</description></item><item><title>Trying Out berry</title><link>https://michaelskyba.github.io/articles/trying-out-berry/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 10:38:12 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://michaelskyba.github.io/articles/trying-out-berry/</guid><description>Introduction Recently, I found out about berry, which describes itself as &amp;ldquo;[a] healthy, byte-sized window manager&amp;rdquo;. As of the time I&amp;rsquo;m writing this, I have used berry for around one day. In this post, I would like to share my first impressions.
Philosophy The main thing that drew me to berry in the first place was its philosophy. dwm, which I was using before trying berry, does not follow the UNIX philosophy as well as I would like.</description></item><item><title>msk_music</title><link>https://michaelskyba.github.io/articles/msk_music/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 22:12:54 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://michaelskyba.github.io/articles/msk_music/</guid><description>I have decided to put this to use for sharing scripts I write, in hopes that one or two of them could be of use to somebody.
msk_music GitHub Gist
msk_music is a simple and featureless way of listening to music. It uses the equivalent of &amp;ldquo;random&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;consume&amp;rdquo; modes on mpd (which it aims to replace). For my use cases, which I believe are fairly standard, it does so successfully.</description></item><item><title>Get a Working Wi-Fi Connection in an Artix Installation</title><link>https://michaelskyba.github.io/articles/artix-wifi-connection/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 21:43:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://michaelskyba.github.io/articles/artix-wifi-connection/</guid><description>While Arch and Gentoo have had internet working mostly out-of-the-box, Artix has not. I thought it could be beneficial if I compiled a list of steps:
1. Become root: su 2. Make an initial wpa_supplicant configuration Create /etc/wpa_supplicant/wpa_supplicant.conf with the following lines:
ctrl_interface=/run/wpa_supplicant update_config=1 3. Make sure rfkill isn&amp;rsquo;t active rfkill unblock wifi 4. Start wpa_supplicant wpa_supplicant -B -i wlan0 -c /etc/wpa_supplicant/wpa_supplicant.conf My device name was &amp;lsquo;wlan0&amp;rsquo;, but you should edit the command if yours is different.</description></item><item><title>Block a Site Using /etc/hosts</title><link>https://michaelskyba.github.io/articles/block-a-site-using-etc-hosts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 18:47:20 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://michaelskyba.github.io/articles/block-a-site-using-etc-hosts/</guid><description>Simply add 0.0.0.0 mysite to your /etc/hosts file.
For example, 0.0.0.0 example.com. Here, example.com will basically be an alias for &amp;ldquo;0.0.0.0&amp;rdquo;, which acts as a dummy address.
Note that this isn&amp;rsquo;t completely reliable. If it&amp;rsquo;s not working, try adding a second entry with &amp;ldquo;www.&amp;rdquo; and also try restarting your browser (in case, for example, you&amp;rsquo;re seeing a cached page).
Here is a list of sites that you may want to block.</description></item></channel></rss>